/* QUESTIONS 
/* Q1: Some of the facilities charge a fee to members, but some do not.
Write a SQL query to produce a list of the names of the facilities that do. */
SELECT * FROM Facilities WHERE membercost > 0;

/* Q2: How many facilities do not charge a fee to members? */
SELECT COUNT(*) FROM Facilities WHERE membercost = 0;

/* Q3: Write an SQL query to show a list of facilities that charge a fee to members,
where the fee is less than 20% of the facility's monthly maintenance cost.
Return the facid, facility name, member cost, and monthly maintenance of the
facilities in question. */
SELECT facid, name, membercost, monthlymaintenance FROM Facilities WHERE membercost > 0 AND membercost < (0.2 * monthlymaintenance);

/* Q4: Write an SQL query to retrieve the details of facilities with ID 1 and 5.
Try writing the query without using the OR operator. */
SELECT * FROM Facilities WHERE facid IN (1,5);

/* Q5: Produce a list of facilities, with each labelled as
'cheap' or 'expensive', depending on if their monthly maintenance cost is
more than $100. Return the name and monthly maintenance of the facilities
in question. */
SELECT name, monthlymaintenance, 
CASE
	WHEN monthlymaintenance < 100 THEN 'cheap'
	ELSE 'expensive' 
	END AS FType
FROM Facilities;
/* Q6: You'd like to get the first and last name of the last member(s)
who signed up. Try not to use the LIMIT clause for your solution. */
SELECT firstname, surname FROM Members ORDER BY joindate LIMIT 1;
SELECT firstname, surname FROM Members ORDER BY joindate DESC LIMIT 1;
/* Q7: Produce a list of all members who have used a tennis court.
Include in your output the name of the court, and the name of the member
formatted as a single column. Ensure no duplicate data, and order by
the member name. */
SELECT DISTINCT CONCAT (Facilities.name, " ", Members.firstname, " ", Members.surname, " ") as Q7Result
	from Members
	INNER JOIN Bookings ON Members.memid = Bookings.memid
	INNER JOIN Facilities ON Bookings.facid = Facilities.facid WHERE Bookings.facid IN ('0','1')
	ORDER BY Members.surname, Members.firstname;

/* Q8: Produce a list of bookings on the day of 2012-09-14 which
will cost the member (or guest) more than $30. Remember that guests have
different costs to members (the listed costs are per half-hour 'slot'), and
the guest user's ID is always 0. Include in your output the name of the
facility, the name of the member formatted as a single column, and the cost.
Order by descending cost, and do not use any subqueries. */

/* Q8: Produce a list of bookings on the day of 2012-09-14 which
will cost the member (or guest) more than $30. Remember that guests have
different costs to members (the listed costs are per half-hour 'slot'), and
the guest user's ID is always 0. Include in your output the name of the
facility, the name of the member formatted as a single column, and the cost.
Order by descending cost, and do not use any subqueries. */

SELECT Facilities.name, CONCAT(Members.firstname," ",Members.surname) AS MName, 
       IF(Members.memid = '0', Bookings.slots * Facilities.guestcost, Bookings.slots * Facilities.membercost ) AS Cost
       FROM Bookings
       INNER JOIN Members ON Bookings.memid=Members.memid 
       INNER JOIN Facilities ON Bookings.facid = Facilities.facid
	   WHERE starttime LIKE '2012-09-14%' 
	   HAVING Cost > '30'
       ORDER BY Cost DESC 
/* Q9: This time, produce the same result as in Q8, but using a subquery. */
SELECT Facilities.name, CONCAT(Members.firstname," ",Members.surname) AS MName,
IF(Members.memid = '0', Bookings.slots * Facilities.guestcost, Bookings.slots * Facilities.membercost ) AS Cost
FROM Bookings
INNER JOIN Members ON Bookings.memid=Members.memid
INNER JOIN Facilities ON Bookings.facid = Facilities.facid
WHERE starttime IN (SELECT starttime FROM Bookings WHERE starttime LIKE '2012-09-14%')
HAVING Cost > '30'
ORDER BY Cost DESC
/*Q10: Produce a list of facilities with a total revenue less than 1000.
The output of facility name and total revenue, sorted by revenue. Remember
that there's a different cost for guests and members!*/
